Guide to the Papers of Serge A. Korff 1928-1989 MC 110 MC 110
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Organizations
  - Subseries B: Conferences
    - Geological Society of America National Meeting, Miami, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Symposia to Honor Dr. Manuel Sandoval Vallarta, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 14th International Cosmic Ray Conference, Munich, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1st Miami Conference on Isotope Climatology and Paleoclimatology, Key Biscayne, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 9th Annual International Radiocarbon Conference, UCLA/UCSD, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 8th Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics, Boston, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 15th International Cosmic Ray Conference, Plodiv, Bulgaria, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 9th Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics, Munchen, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Harbor Branch Foundation Meeting, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 16th International Cosmic Ray Conference, Kyoto, Japan, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 10th Annual International Radiocarbon Conference, Berne and Heidelberg, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Three-Mile Island Conference, NYAS, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 10th Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics, Baltimore, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 17th International Cosmic Ray Conference, Paris, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - 11th Annual International Radiocarbon Conference, Seattle, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Space Science and Technology Symposium (proposed to WAAS), 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - International Conference on Information Revolution, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 12th Annual Texas Symposium on Relativistic Astrophysics, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Management of Pain and Stress, WAAS, Washington D.C., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1933-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Series V: Academia
  - Subseries A: New York University
    (arranged topically; includes restricted materials, departmental and interdepartmental communications, class outlines, lecture notes, lectures)
    - Departmental and interdepartmental correspondence, 1951-1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - "History of NYU Physics Department 1940-1970", 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Physical Optics 251/252, course materials, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Experimental Nuclear Physics 207/208 (later 2207/2208), exams, 1948-1972, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Experimental Nuclear Physics 2297, lecture notes, ca.1948-19[72] (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Experimental Nuclear Physics 2298, lecture notes, ca.1948-19[72] (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous course materials, 1952-1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Physics of the Upper Atmosphere 209, course materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Theory of Spectra 253, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Astronomy and Astrophysics, exams, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Cosmic Ray Program, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - "Introduction to Radiological Safety," Post-Graduate Medical School and College of Engineering cooperative lectures, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - "The High Energy Universe," special resident lectureship in physics, ca. 1960 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous lectures, 1950-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Subseries B: Student work
    - List of dissertations and theses supervised, ca.1970 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Student papers and abstracts, 1947-1948, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Student grades, 1958-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225413 9
      restricted
    - Hakner, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kitchen, Sumner W. "Negative Ions and Long Delays...", 1950 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Krumbien, Aaron Davis, "Self-quenching Counters", 1951 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lerner, Alberto de la Zerda, thesis proposal, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Radin, Jonathan, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Soicher, Haim, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Spatz, Wilbur de Villa Bernhart, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Witten, Arnold, "Geiger Counters with NH3 Fillings", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subseries C: Other Universities
    - Environmental Science Program, UCLA, 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University: Board of Trustees, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University: Board of Trustees Meeting, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Publications
  - Subseries A: Bibliographies
    - Bibliographies, ca. 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: Korff reprints, preprints, and abstracts
    (arranged chronologically; where Korff is the sole author, his name does not appear, and for co-authored articles, Korff's initials "SAK" appear)
    - Refractive Index of Sodium Vapor and Width of D1 in Absorptions: Apr. 1929 Dispersion and Absorption Line Width inthe Alkali Vapors: Aug. 1929 A Sensitive Method for Determining Refractive Indices, SAK and J. Q. Stewart: Jun. 1930 Scattering of Light in Sodium Vapor: Jan. 1930 Distinction between Scattering and Absorption, SAK and John Q. Stewart: Jan. 1930, 1921-1930 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Absorption Line Width in Sodium Vapor: Aug. 1931 Optical Dispersion, SAK and F. Breit: Jul-32 On the Measurement and Interpretation of Fraunhofer Lines: 1932 Widthof the D Lines of Sodium in Absorption: 1932 Letter to Scientific American, v. 148, no. 296: May 1933 Note by SAK on Eclipse Cinematography, Paul Bourgeois and J. F. Cox: Jun. 1933 Density of Energy in the Universe: Aug. 1933 Azimuthal Asymmetry of Cosmic Radiation: Sep. 1933 Penetrating Power of Asymmetric Component of Cosmic Radiation: Jul. 1934 Cosmic-Ray Observations in the Stratosphere, SAK and L. F. Curtiss, A. V. Astin, L. L. Stockmann and B. W. Brown: Jan. 1938. Bursts in Cosmic Radiation in the Equatorial Zone: Sep. 1938 Discussion of Present Status of the Theory of the Effect of the Earth's Magnetic Field on Cosmic Rays by M. S. Vallarta, Sc. D, Ph. D.: Jan. 1939. Neutron Measurements with Boron-Trifluoride Counters: May 1939 Correlation of Counter and Electroscope Measurements of Cosmic Radiation in the Stratosphere, SAK and W. E. Danforth: Aug. 1939 The Upward Radiation Produced by Cosmic Rays at High Altitudes, SAK and E. T. Clarke: Oct. 1939 Cosmic-Ray Investigations: Dec. 1939 Fast Neutron Measurements with Recoil Counters: Dec. 1939 On the Interpretation of Neutron Measurements in Cosmic Radiation, SAK, H. A. Bethe and G. Placzek: April 1940. Solar Influences on the Cosmic Ray Intensity at High Elevations: Jun-40 On the Contribution to the Ionization at Sea-level Produced by the Neutrons in the Cosmic Radiation: Jun. 1940 The Latitude Effect in Cosmic Rays at Far Southern Latitudes, SAK and E. T. Clarke: Jul. 1940 Use of a Grid to Reduce Operating Voltage in Geiger-Mueller Counters, SAK and W. E. Ramsey: Aug. 1940 Report of Cosmic Ray Observations Made on the U. S. Antarctic Expedition in Cooperation with the Bartol Research Foundation, SAK and E. T. Clarke: Nov. 1940 Cosmic-Ray Investigations: Dec. 1940 Report on Penrose Grant No. 363 Investigation of the disruption of the nuclei in the upper atmosphere by cosmic radiation: 1940., 1931-1940 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fast Neutrons and Particles with High Specific Ionization in the Cosmic Radiation at High Elevations: Jan. 1941 Operation of Proportional Counters: Feb. 1941 An Investigation of the Properties of Proportional Counters. I, SAK and M. E. Rose: Jun. 1941 Nuclear Particles in the Cosmic Radiation: Jun. 1941 The Production of Neutrons by the Cosmic Radiation: Jul. 1941 Cosmic. 19 Ray Investigations: Dec. 1941 Report on Penrose Grant No. 504 Cosmic ray investigations in connection with the United States Antarctic Service: 1941 The Operation of Proportional Counters: Jan. 1942 Temperature Coefficients in Self-Quenching Counters, SAK, W. D. B. Spatz, and N. Hilberry: Mar. 1942 The Production of Neutrons and Protons by the Cosmic Radiation at 14,125 Feet, SAK and E. T. Clarke: Apr. 1942 Cosmic. 19 Ray Investigations: Dec. 1942 Cosmic. 19 Ray Investigations: Dec. 1943 A Note on Fluctuations in the Cosmic Radiation Observed in Connection with Magnetic Storms: Dec. 1943 On the Role of Polyatomic Gases in Fast Counters, SAK and R. D. Present: May. 1944 Cosmic Ray Investigations at New York University: Dec. 1944 Report on Cosmic. 19 Ray Observations made on the United States Antarctic Service Expedition, 1939. 191941, SAK, Capt. Dana K. Bailey, and Eric T. Clark: Apr. 1945 Experiments on Counters with Grids: Jul. 1945 Cosmic Ray Research at New York University: Dec. 1945, 1941-1945 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Electron and Nuclear Counters: Theory and Use (unbound signatures), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - The Energy Distribution and Number of Cosmic. Ray Neutrons in the Free Atmosphere, SAK and B. Hamermesh: Mar. 1946 New Cosmic Ray Radiosonde Techniques, SAK and B. Hamermesh: May. 1946 Cosmic Ray Investigations at New York University: Dec. 1946 The Production of Nucleons by the Cosmic Radiation: Jun. 1947 Comments on F. H. J. Figge: Jun. 1947 On the Rise of the Wire. 19 Potential in Counters: Sep. 1947 A Photoelectric Hygrometer, SAK, Bernard Hamermesh, and Frederick Reines: Sep. 1947 Electronic Techniques in Nuclear Science: Dec. 1947 The Production of Nuclear Disruptions by the Cosmic Radiation: Jan. 1948 The Production of Nucleons by the Cosmic Radiation. II, SAK and A. Coras: May. 1948 The Energy Distribution of Neutrons in the Atmosphere, SAK, M.S. George, and J.W. Kerr: May. 1948 Detecting Atomic Particles: Jun. 1948 A Critique of Ionization Measurements of Nuclear Disruptions Produced by Cosmic Radiation: Jan. 1949 Tests of Self-Regenerating Fillings for Geiger Counters, SAK and A.D. Krumbein: Nov. 1949 The Genesis of Cosmic Radiation: Jan. 1950 Cosmic Radiation and the Maintainance of a Potential Gradient in the Atmosphere: Jan. 1950, 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - The Latitude Effect of Cosmic Neutrons, SAK, W.P. Staker and M. Pavalow: Mar. 1951 Cosmic Ray Neutrons: Apr. 1951 Science Education as an Ambassador of Good Will: Nov. 1951 The World's High-Altitude Laboratories: May. 1952 The Mount Wrangell Observatory: Oct. 1953 Deterioration of Boron Trifluoride Counters Due to High Counting Rates, SAK, Robert K. Soberman, Stephen S. Friedland and Henry S. Katzenstein: Nov. 1953 Effects of the Cosmic Radiation on Terrestrial Isotope Distribution: Feb. 1954 Effect of the Melting of Polar Ice on the Length of the Day: Jul. 1954 High-Altitude Cosmic-Ray Neutron Density at the Geomagnetic Pole, SAK, H.A.C. Newburg, R.K. Soberman and M.J. Swetnick: Mar. 1955 Report to Cosmic Ray Conference at Guanajuato, Mexico: Sep. 1955, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - The World's High-Altitude Research Stations, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Nuclear Techniques Will Aid International Geophysical Year: Feb. 1956 The Effects of Cosmic Rays on the Terrestrial Isotope Distribution: Sep. 1956 Physics in South America: Dec. 1956 The Origin and Implications of the Cosmic Radiation: Sep.1957 Geiger Counters: 1958 Plateau Slopes and Pulse Characteristics of Large, High-Pressure B F3 Counters, SAK and R.B. Mendell: Jun. 1959 Bariloche Cosmic-Ray Conference, SAK and Robert L. Chasson: Jul. 1959 Geographical Aspects of Cosmic-Ray Studies: 1960 Effect of Gaseous Impurities on B F3 Proportional Counters, SAK and J. Davila Aponte: May. 1960 High Neutron and Radiation Intensities at Balloon Altitudes during Auroral Display, SAK and R.C. Haymes: Oct. 1960 Slow-Neutron Intensity at High Balloon Altitudes, SAK and R.C. Haymes: Nov. 1960, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - A Measurement of Slow Cosmic-Ray Neutrons up to 200 Kilometers, SAK, W.P. Reidy and R.C. Haymes: Feb.1962 Observations at College, Alaska, of the November, 1960 Cosmic Ray Increases: 1962 Tritium Content of Antarctic Snow, SAK, S.P. Shen and H.A.C. Neuburg: Jul. 1963 Cosmic Rays or Machines?: Sep. 1963 Fast-Neutron Flux in the Atmosphere, SAK and R.B. Mendell: Oct. 1963 Fast-Neutron Detector with Discrimination against Background Radiation, SAK and R.B. Mendell: Dec. 1963. Production for Neutrons by Cosmic Radiation The Natural Radiation Environment, J. A. Adams and W.M. Lowder, eds.: 1964 Cosmic-Ray Expedition to India: Jun. 1965 Eclipse of Sun seen by our Man in Tahiti: Aug. 1965 The Scientific Report of the Rockwell Polar Flight: 1965 Measurements ofneutrons produced by the cosmic radiation, SAK, R.B. Mendell and S.S. Holt: 1965, 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Cosmic Radiation (technical report of the NYU Cosmic Ray Group), 1962 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Cosmic Ray Neutrons (from Essays in Honor of Hans A. Bethe): 1966 Fast Neutron Latitude Variations in the Atmosphere at Solar Minimum, SAK, S.S. Holt and R.B. Mendell: Nov. 1966 Cosmic-ray fast-neutron flux measurements in the atmosphere at various latitudes, SAK, R.B. Mendell, M. Merker, and W. Sandie: Jun. 1967 Cosmic Ray Atmospheric Neutron Measurements at High Elevations over a Sunspot Cycle, SAK and Rosalind B. Mendell: 1969 The Flux of Fast Neutrons in the Atmosphere. 1. The Effect of Solar Modulation of Galactic Cosmic Rays, SAK, R.B. Mendell, M. Merker and E.S. Light: 1969 The Flux of Fast Neutrons in the Atmosphere. 2. Solar Flare Effects, SAK, R.B. Mendell, M. Merker and E.S. Light: 1969 Analysis of Annual and Semi-Annual Periodicities in Neutron Monitor Data, SAK and S.M. Schneider: 1969 Investigation of Cosmic-Ray Produced Fast Neutrons in the Atmosphere, SAK, R.B. Mendell, M. Merker and E.S. Light: 1970 A Literature Survey of Recent Articles on Geiger Mueller Counters and Gas-discharge Phenomena Associated with their Operation, SAK and S. Wistosky Sep. 1968, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - A Literature Survey of Recent Articles on Geiger Mueller Counters and Gas-discharge Phenomena Associated with their Operation, SAK and S. Wistosky Sep. 1968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Continue the Support of Science!: 1971 Spallation Cross Sections at 920 Me V(230 Me V/N) in 27 Al, 16 O, 12 C and 9 Be, and Application to Cosmic Ray Transport," March 1971. SAK, Jonathan R. Radin, Alan R. Smith and Nickey Little. A Physicist Looks at Geographical and Environmental Problems: Jun. 1971 Photography of the Eclipse of 7 March, 1970, from Two Locations SAK and R.B. Mendell: 1971 Two Classes of Forbush Decreases, SAK, Howard J. Verschell, Rosalind B. Mendell and Edmond C. Roelof: 1971 Observations of the Cosmic Ray Modulation from Neutron Measurements at the High Latitude Transition Maximum, SAK, Howard J. Verschell and Rosalind B. Mendell: 1971 Solar Modulation of Atmospheric Flux, Experiment and Calculation, SAK, Edward S. Light, Milton Merker and Rosalind B. Mendell: 1971 The Revenue Stamps of the U. S. Virgin Islands: 1971 Time Dependent Worldwide Distributionof Atmospheric Neutrons and of Their Products. 1. Fast Neutron Observations, SAK, M. Merker E.S. Light, H. J. Verschell and R.B. Mendell: Jun. 1973 Cosmic Rays and Neutrons (from 1974 symposium honoring Dr. Vallarta): 1975 Two Classes of Cosmic Ray Decrease, SAK, H.J. Verschell, R.B. Mendell and E.C. Roelof: Apr. 1975 Cosmic Rays and Eclipses: Sep. 1975 Geophysics: Another Facet of the Unity of Nature: 1976 Variation in the Radiocarbon Production Rates, SAK and Rosalind B. Mendell: 1976 Kerfluffle: Jul. 1977 Use of English as the Language of Science: 1978 English language for scientific communication: 1979 Variations in Radiocarbon Production in the Earth's Atmosphere, SAK and Rosalind B. Mendell: 1980, 1971-1980 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Ambient Radiation Levels: 1981 Cosmic Ray Neutrons, 1934-59: 1985 Counters: n.d. The Importance of Manned Exploration in Space: n.d. Ionizing Radiation at 40 K M S Altitude During Auroral Display, SAK and Robert Haymes: n.d. Measurements of the Neutrons Produced by the Cosmic Radiation, SAK, Rosalind B. Mendell, and Stephen S. Holt: n.d. Some Comments on Atmospheric Neutron Measurements: n.d., undated, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Promotional materials, 1952-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Kodak promotional materials, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Travel brochures and maps, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Subseries C: Reprints, preprints and abstracts (non-Korffian)
    - Reprints, undated (Box 7, Folder 1 (31))
    - Reprints, 1932-1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225414 7
    - Reprints, 1941-1950 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Reprints, 1951-1956 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Reprints, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Reprints, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Reprints, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Reprints, 1967-1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Reprints, 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Reprints, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Subseries D: Publications
    - Publications, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Publications, 1950-1959 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Publications, 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Publications, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Publications, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 15)